Guide to the Emma L. Phillips McDivitt photograph albums, [ca.1900-1926]
McDivitt, Emma L. Phillips photograph albums, [ca.1900-1926]
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Emma L. Phillips McDivitt photograph albums, [ca.1900-1926].
4125
Emma L. Phillips McDivitt, 1876-[ca.1955].
.3 cubic ft.
Photograph albums
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Three albums of photographs taken primarily by Emma McDivitt, but also containing John P. Troy and Ernest Abbe photographs, of Cornell University students and campus scenes, family gatherings, as well as scenes from her travels in Europe and East Asia. Other subjects include the solar eclipse of January 1925 and the unveiling of the Ezra Cornell statue at Cornell University.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Emma L. Phillips of Dumont, New Jersey married Dr. John McDivitt, who died in 1911. Following his death, Mrs. McDivitt moved to Ithaca, Tompkins County, New York, where her cousin, Jennie Sewell Linson Horton lived in an area called Forest Home. McDivitt was employed at the New York State Extension Office, Roberts Hall, Cornell University, from 1919 to 1930.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Three albums of photographs taken primarily by Emma McDivitt, but also containing John P. Troy and Ernest Abbe photographs, of Cornell University students and campus scenes, family gatherings, as well as scenes from her travels in Europe and East Asia. Includes photographs of the Bowers, Linson, Phillips, Reynolds, Snook and Westervelt families and the Horton family of Ithaca, Tompkins County, New York, at weddings and other family gatherings; also of rural and urban street scenes. Other subjects include the solar eclipse of January 1925; the unveiling of the Ezra Cornell statue at Cornell University; Long Island College Hospital; U.S. Marine Hospital, Detroit, Michigan; and various views in Ithaca, Tompkins County, Watkins Glen, Schuyler County and Sullivan County, New York. Also, photographs of Brooklyn, New York; Dumont and Trenton, New Jersey; the Philippine Islands; Seoul, Korea; the Ming tombs in China; and other views of the Far East and Western Europe; and photographs of individuals, some Cornell staff and students, including Harding Fred Horton (Cornell University Class of 1917) in his freshman beanie; Clarence Dagnall (Cornell University M.S. 1922); Lucretia Hinkley Ferguson (Cornell University Class of 1919); Charles Evans Hughes; Merton Jones (Cornell University Class of 1921); Marcus Aurelius McMaster (Cornell University Class of 1921); Merrill H. Moore; George H. Rekate (Cornell University Class of 1907); Alfred Emmanuel Smith
Wilmer Cressman Swartly (Cornell University Class of 1930); and McDivitt's husband John McDivitt.
SUBJECTS
Names:
McDivitt, Emma L. Phillips,1876-[ca.1955].; Abbe, Ernest.; Bowers family.; Dagnall, Clarence.; Ferguson, Lucretia Hinckley.; Horton family.; Horton, Harding Fred, d.1918.; Horton, Jennie Sewell Linson.; Hughes, Charles Evans.; Jones, Merton.; Linson family.; McDivitt, John, d. 1911.; McMaster, Marcus Aurelius.; Moore, Merrill H.; Phillips family.; Rekate, George H.; Reynolds family.; Smith, Alfred Emmanuel.; Snook family.; Swartly, Wilmer Cressman.; Troy, John P.; Westervelt family.; Cornell University--Description--Views.; Cornell University--Students.; Cornell University.Cooperative Extension.; Long Island College Hospital.; U.S. Marine Hospital (Detroit, Mich.).
Subjects:
Cities and towns.; Solar eclipses; Families.; Farm life.; Weddings.; World War, 1914-1918.; Photographs.
Places:
Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.).; China.; Dumont (N.J.).; East Asia.; Europe.; Ithaca (N.Y.).; Philippine Islands.; Schuyler County (N.Y.); Seoul (Korea).; Sullivan County (N.Y.); Tompkins County (N.Y.); Trenton (N.J.).; Watkins Glen (N.Y.).
INFORMATION FOR USERS
SERIES LIST
Series I. Black album, smaller of 2
Series II. Black album, larger of 2
Series III. Green album
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Black album, smaller of 2
  - Cascadilla Bridge in snow
  - World War I - Review on Alumni Field
  - World War I - Drill Hall
  - World War I - Men in uniform marching past Sage and Barnes toward Cascadilla Bridge
  - World War I - Drill day on Campus [J. P. Troy]
  - World War I - Col. Barton reviewing troop
  - Insterted among the above: 1919 Mud Rush [Troy photo]
  - Campus scenes, esp. snow, ca. 1920 - various - library Tower, Cascadilla Bridge
  - Commencement Day Parade
  - Entering Bailey for Comm. [Troy ph.]
  - Girls' crew on Beebe Lake, 1917/1918
  - Excursion steamer on Cayuga Lake
  - Jennie Horton, Mrs. Stevenson - Forest Home - 1918 - various - also, Emma McDivitt, Mary Johnson
  - Fred Horton as Freshman [1913]
  - Fred Linson, Merle Linson, others, Forest Home - various
  - Fred on campus; Jennie, ditto; at Renwick Park
  - Jennie, Emma, Mary Johnson at CrowBar Point, on steamer
  - Spring Day 1920 - Merton Jones and Marcus McMaster [both CU '21] - several
  - "The Old Tunnel," Ithaca
  - Ithaca Falls, Enfield Glen
  - Ferguson and Rekate families at table - wedding luncheon of Lucretia Ferguson '19 & George H. Rekate '07
  - Unveiling statue of Ezra Cornell
  - Semi-Centennial in Drill Hall
  - Group photo of Chas. Evans Hughes, ?, Alfred E. Smith, Schurman, ?.
  - More drill photos - Forest Home Drive and Arts quad. - 3 views
  - Watkins Glen - 3 views
  - Social groups - wiener roast at Buttermilk, April 1921, etc.
  - Mrs. Lucretia [Hinkley] Ferguson in cap & gown, 1919-20 - [AB 19 (later Mrs. George H. Rekate; he was CE 03-07, d.'56)]
  - Emma McD., Mabel Terhune, and Mrs. ? Moore in front of Franklin Hall, 1923
  - Wedding of Clarence [CU, MS '22] and Veda Jones Dagnall, attended by Merton Jones and Edith Voorhees [24 AB]
  - M[arcus] A[urelius] McMaster
  - Veda Jones in rowboat on Cayuga Lake
  - Child, Norman Hungerford
  - Merrill H. Moore [21-22 Agr.]
  - Mrs. Moore, Melissa Miller, Emma McD., others on porch of Alpha Zeta
  - Skiing on Williams Street, looking NW with Cascadilla Hall in Background
  - The Dagnalls and Veda's parents at 106 Highland Pl.
  - View from upstairs window at 106 Highland, where McD. aparently lived
  - Highland Place snowed in, 1925 - one taken by Ernest Abbe [probably Ernst Abbe, '28]
  - Roaring Branch Brook
  - Veda and Junior Dagnall - several; also Bobby D., younger brother [?]
  - Cascadilla Creek
  - Melissa Miller; house at 106 Highland Place
  - Aerial view of CU, J.P. Troy
  - Eclipse of sun, January 24, 1925, taken from Botany Dept. windows - 2 views
  - Emma; Lotta Bailey, Louise Barnard - several
  - Another view of eclipse
  - Snow scene from office window in Roberts, 25/26
  - Other campus snow scenes
  - Ralph Tarr boulder near Morrill
  - Sun dial south of GS Hall
  - Sage Chapel; men's dorms at foot of Libe slope
  - "Sham battle - Cayuga Lake" - men in uniform w. cannon overlooking lake
  - Enfield Glen, Buttermilk Glen
  - Totem pole on campus
  - Ithaca Falls
  - Blanche Monroe, Nellie Van Dyne, and Melissa Miller in front of Roberts Hall
- Series II. Black album, larger of 2
  - Hamburg-American Line, pier, Hoboken, June 11, 1907
  - Various views on board the Hamburg - Emma, Nettie, Mr. Snook
  - Azores, Gibralter
  - Bedrm. in Naples hotel; Capri
  - Italian woman and baby at Capri; Pompeii
  - Several pp. on rome - Colosseum, St. Peter's, etc.
  - Appian way; Italian stove
  - Unident. - but appears to be Baptistery in Florence
  - Pisa
  - Venice - several pp.
  - Milan: incl. "Last Supper"
  - On train to Switzerland
  - Italian Lake Distr.
  - Interlaken
  - Holland
  - Paris, Versailles
  - Shot of a stowaway being returned to land by Pilot boat from the Minnehaha, July 28, 1907
  - Views of Shokan, NY - RR st., yoke of oxen, logs on wagon falls; Emma Phillips at West Shokan
  - Steamer Portland, John [MD] and Emma on board; same at Old Orchard Beach, Maine
  - Group of Americans and views in Philippine Islands. (refs. to Harry and Southern Island Hospital at Cebu, 1915)
  - J. H. Linson at Ming tombs, Sept. 1917
  - Hotel in Seoul, Korea
  - Shot of the Am. schooner Irmgard, picked up in distres off the E. coast of Formosa by the U.S. ?? Thomas following typhoon of Aug. 18-21, 1917
  - Views of US Marine Hospital, Detroit
  - Reynolds (related to Linsons?) family - Wayne, Nebraska - several
  - Phillips cottage, white Lake, NY; - several
  - Emma L. Phillips at age 16 with cat at White Lake
  - More White Lake [Sullivan Co.] views
  - Aunt Jane Ann [Westervelt], Mongaup Valley [Sullivan County] - with elderly man by pump; Aunt in sunbonnet. Also shot of Aunt in dark dress and white bonnet
  - Westervelt farm, same place - plowing, etc.
  - Horton Home, White Lake
  - Various group photos at White Lake - Jennie, Emma, Fred, etc. - fishing; cat and the bait box!
  - McIntyres at Ferndale - haying, barn, etc. - numerous
  - Schooner (3 masts) on Hudson River
  - Phillips house in Brooklyn - construction of Williamsburg Bridge; moving an apt. house
  - Trenton, NJ - factory or warehouse, soldiers' monument, Quaker church, library; flood damage, train wreck, etc.
  - Patterson, Lakewood, NJ
  - Family groups, Dumont, NJ, 1907 inc. John McDivitt and Emma
  - Medical students on roof of Long Island College Hospital
  - More Phillips house and family
  - Dr. McDivitt with Model T, Dumont, NJ
  - Bull dog - "Honey King"; other dog, "Taffy"
  - Children of friends and family, NJ, Brooklyn, etc., Linsons, Kleinstubers, Aunt Lizzie Peloubet; more McDivitt
  - Many of wedding of Frank McD. and Florence Emke [sp?] in Trenton
  - Wedding, Horace and Mabel ?, West Haven, Conn.
  - House in Goshen, NY
  - Homes of relatives in Dumont, Brooklyn, Auburndale, Mass., Conn. coast, etc.
  - More at Hortons' in Forest Home, white frame house - [still there, I think]
  - Other Hortons, McD., Hungerfords, Forest Home, campus, etc., etc.
- Series III. Green album
  - Roberts Hall, complex
  - Phelps and Wintringham families, visitors on CU campus
  - Watkins Glen, Susquehanna River at Smithboro
  - Emma & women friends
  - Lotta Bailey, Elizabeth Lyman, Addie Bolling, etc. Fanny Grennell; cat Rusty; on excursions to Seneca Lake, Geneva, etc. in 1 seater Model T
  - Union Springs in snow - U.S.L. & P. office
  - Lucretia Rekate [nee Ferguson]
  - Claire Snook, age 12 (boy), other Snook children
  - Birmingham, Mich. - Clarence & Nettie Snook farm and family
  - Wilmer C. Swartley, Jr. on motorcycle, Ithaca [S. Aurora]
  - "Boys" at 106 highland Pl. - 1920? - some in uniform Trip to Chicago and by boat to Milwaukee
  - Emma & Nellie Stewart at YWCA, Chicago
  - Lyman Linson's in Charles Town, W. Va. - [late 20's]
  - Mother and self and Mother and Bert at West Pt. [early - these are not in chron. order]
  - John and self at Dumont, NJ; RR station & mother's home there
  - Friends and relatives [Dumont?]
  - Western scenes takes by Merton Jones
  - More on bd. the Hamburg, June 1907
  - More Capri and Pompeii, Amsterdam, The Hague, other Holland; Italian Lake District; Venice, Versailles, Parliment, Big Ben
  - Leaving England, August 07
  - Undated Commencement procession, CU; Minnie Linson; Louise Barnard, Emma at 106 Highland
  - Mrs. Barnes, Miss Graves, Mrs. McDivitt, at 106
  - Patricia German - little girl
  - Other Dagnall, Dunn, Bower; Fred Horton, 1913 & WWI. [CU '17; killed France, Oct. 1918]
  - Early group at Patchogue - Bowers, etc.